Printed Maps Printed.Maps
American Philosophical Society
- Europe
  - France
    - France divided into circles and departments. Philadelphia: J. Stewart & Co.: 1798 [17 February 1798]., 260; Scale: 1⅛ in. = 60 British statute mi.; Size: 31.4 x 35.5 cm.
      See: John Gifford [John Richards Green], The history of France. 1798, vol. 4, frontispiece.
    - Plan of part of a line of circumvallation [of Arras in 1654]. 1798., 261; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 55 fathoms.; Size: 3 x 17 cm.; A. Lauson [Lawson].
      Inset: Profile of same.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 18, following p. 768.
      Wheat: 813
    - A new and accurate map of France divided into departments, with the Netherlands &c. 1799., 262; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 75 mi.; Size: 21.5 x 22.3 cm.; A. Anderson.
      Inset: Plan of Toulon &c.
      In: John Payne, A new and complete system of universal geography, vol. 3, opposite p. 607.
      Wheat: 839
    - Atlas topographique en XVI feuilles des environs de Paris, à la distance d'environ 8 myriamètres, ou 18 lièves... par Dom G. Coutans... revu, corrigé & considerablement augmenté, d'après nombre de cartes precieuses & plans particuliers... par Charles Picquet, géograph. graveur. Paris: C. Picquet: 1800. 16 folding maps in 2 volumes., 263; Scale: 3.1 cm. = 2 km.; Size: 38 x 61.5 cm.; Charles Picquet.; G. Coutans and Charles Picquet.
      Engraved title page contains index map: Tableau d'assemblage.
      Received 1 March 1805.
    - Plan routier de la ville et faubourg de Paris divisé en 12 mairies, 1800. [Paris]: Jean: 1800., 264; Scale: 3.7 cm. = 200 toises.; Size: 55.3 x 84.8 cm.; Colored.
      Legacy of and endorsed by Thomas Peters Smith, 1802.
    - Nouveau plan routier de la ville et faubourgs de Paris avec ses principaux édifices et nouvelles barriers. Par M. Pichon, Ingénieur Géographe. Paris: Esnault: 1801 An 9., 265; Scale: 13.7 cm. = 500 toises.; Size: 99.8 x 142 cm.; Colored.; C. B. Glot and E. Voysard.; Pichon.
      Inset: Some of the splendid views of Paris and environs.
    - Carte de l'empire Français et des états limitrophes, dessinée par Hérisson, Ingénieur Géographe. Revue, corrigée et augmentée par H. Brué. Paris: Desray et J. Goujon: 1813., 266; Scale: 25 French common leagues = 1 degree.; Size: 125 x 193 cm.; Eustache Hérisson and A. H. Brué.
    - Carte pour l'intelligence de la route d'Annibal, depuis le passage du Rhône jusqu' à Turin. N.p.: [ca. 1820]., 267; Scale: 2283 toises = 1 league.; Size: 16.8 x 19.3 cm.; Ambroise Tardieu.
    - Carte de la France divisée en 86 départemens et en 27 cours royales. Paris: Selves Fils, Lithographe: 1821., 1822.; 268; Scale: 25 au dégré.; Size: 7 x 21.4 cm.; Colored.; Selves fils.
      Presented by Comte jean D. Lanjuinais, August 1826 (?).
    - Plano de la Bahia de S[a]n Juan de Luz levantado en 1826 por los Ingenieros Hidrografos de la Marina Francesa. Publicado en la Dirección de Hidrografia. Madrid: 1850., 268a; Scale: 2.5 cm. = .02 nautical mi.; Size: 58 x 41.5 cm.; J. Noguera and F. Bregante.
      Presented by Madrid, Spain, Direcciόn de Hidrografia, 19 October 1852.
    - France. Philadelphia: H. S. Tanner: [ca. 1833]., 269; Scale: 69½ British statute mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 22.7 x 27.6 cm.; Colored.; H. S. Tanner.; J. Knight.
      Inset: Corsica.
      See: H. S. Tanner, Universal atlas. Philadelphia: Tanner: 1833.
    - Vues & coupes du Cap de la Hève. Profit du Cap. Le Havre: Lemercier: 1843., 270; Size: 45.3 x 62.5 cm.; Charles A. Lesueur.
      Presented by Charles A. Lesueur, 14 February 1845.
    - Carte géologique de la France. Ministère des Travaux Publiques. [Paris]: Erhard fres.: [ca. 1875]. Planches 11-21., 271; Scale: 1:10,000.; Size: Various sizes.; Colored.; Elie de Beaumont and Dufrénoy.; L. Wuhrer.
      In separate folder: "Les assises crétaciques et tertiaries du nord de la France." Fasc. III (Region de Béthune).
      Le Bureau des Travaux Publiques de France presented on 21 October 1864 six sheets of "La Carte Géologique de la France." Dufrénoy and Elie de Beaumont prepared the map from 1841 through 1848. [Donation book].
    - Monographic géologique des anciens glaciers et du terrain érratique de la partie moyenne du bassin du Rhône par A. Falsan & E. Chantre. Lyon: Pitrat aîné: 1875. 6 maps in original wrappers., 272; Size: 54.2 x 85 cm.; Colored.; A. Falsan and E. Chantre.
    - Plan de la ville de Paris. Période révolutionnaire [1790-1794]. Ce plan a été exécuté conformément a la décision prise par le conseil municipal de Paris dans sa séance du 30 Décembre 1887. [Paris: 1887]., 273; Scale: 1 cm. = 1,000 m.; Size: 79.2 x 99.5 cm.; Colored.; Lucien Faucou, Laporte, Bibert, and Bizard.; Wuhrer and Sulpis.
    - Plan de la ville de Paris en 1789. Ce plan a été exécuté conformément à la décision prise par le conseil municipal de Paris dans sa séance du 30 Décembre 1887. [Paris: 1887]., 274; Scale: 1 cm. = 1,000 m.; Size: 79.6 x 99.6 cm.; Colored.; Lucien Faucou, Laporte, Bibert, and Bizard.; Wuhrer and Sulpis.
    - Bartholomew's map of north-eastern France, Belgium and the Rhine. The Edinburgh Geographical Institution. Edinburgh: John Bartholomew, & Co.: [ca. 1915]., 275; Scale: 1:1,000,000 or 1 in. = 16 English mi.; Size: 54.3 x 74.1 cm.; Colored.
  - Central Europe
    - [Lon]gitudinal section of the first 38 2/3 English miles of the railway for joining the [Mol]dau and the Danube... with the Elbe, and the Black Sea with the northern ocean, by means of the continent, executed under the superintendence of [the Ch]evalier Francis Anthony Gerstner. The [ac]t of the Emperor of Austria was... 1824, the work begun 28, July 1825 and the 38 2/3 english miles were completely finished at the end of the year 1828. N.p.: [ca. 1830]., 276; 5 sheets.; Size of paper: each ca. 59.5 x 72 cm.
      Insets: Transverse section of an excavation; A horse takes 3 waggons, each loaded with 2 or 2 ½ tons and goes with his load on a level railway 20 English miles in one day; and Transverse section of an embankment, shewing the dry-walling in the middle.
      Presented by the Rev. Mr. Barry.
    - Strassen-Karte des Koenigreiches Ungarn. Vienna: 1832., 277; Scale: 1 Wiener Zoll = 6,000 Wiener Klafter.; Size: 128 x 189.3 cm.; Colored.; A. Floder, Wien.
      Presented by Károly Nagy, 20 August 1833.
    - Geognostische Karte der Umgebungen von Krems und vom Manhardsberge. Im Flächenraume von 34 Quadrat Meilen von Joh. Czjzek, aufgenommen in Monaten August, September, October 1849. N.p.: 1849., 278; Scale: 1 Meile = 4 Zoll.; Size: 69.1 x 88.8 cm.; Colored.; Joh. Czjzek.
      Contains geological profiles, etc.
    - Carte géologique des parties de la Savoie, du Piédmont et de la Suisse voisines du Mont-Blanc. Par Alphonse Favre. Winterthur: J. Wurster et Cie.: 1862., 279; Scale: 1:150,000.; Size: 81.8 x 62.4 cm.; Colored.; Alphonse Favre.
      Contains: Explication des signes et des couleurs, and Hauteurs principales au dessus de la mer.
    - Plan der K. K. Chaussée und der im Bau begriffenen Eisenbahn von Budweis bis zum Scheidungspunkte bei Leopoldschlag nebst ihren nächsten Umgebungen. Vienna: Laurenz Herr and H. F. Müller: [ca. 1865]., 280; Scale: Prifils, 1 Zoll = 1200 Klafter.; Size: 50.6 x 70.8 cm.; Colored.; Casimir von V. Pilarski.; E. K Fruüwirth.
    - [Geological profile maps of the Alps]. Winterthur: Wurster, Randegger: [ca. 1873]., 281; 4 maps.; Sizes: 25.7 x 51.6; 25.6 x 43.5; 25 x 50.4; 24.5 x 73.2 cm.; Colored.
    - Map of Central Europe prepared in the War College Division, General Staff. Washington: Norris Peters Co.: 1914., 282; Scale: 4.7 cm. = 100 km.; Size: 124.3 x 112.5 cm.
      Shows population, army, and reserves for Triple Alliance and Triple Entente; also Vessels building or authorized.
    - Map showing Franco-German frontier. Prepared in the War College Division, General Staff. August 1914., 283; Scale: 2 cm. = 10 mi.; Size: 64.6 x 77.5 cm.
      Includes parts of Switzerland, Belgium, and all of Luxembourg.
    - Strategic map of Central Europe showing the international frontiers. Prepared in the War College Division, General Staff War Department. Washington: Eckert Lithographing Co.: 1915., 284; Scale: 1:2,280,960.; Size: 145.1 x 178.5 cm.; Colored.; Arch. B. Williams & George F. Bontz, draftsmen.
    - Central Europe and the Mediterranean as of September 1, 1939. Compiled and drawn in the cartographic section of the National Geographic Society for the National Geographic Magazine. Gilbert Grosvenor, editor. Baltimore: A. Hoen & Company: 1939., 285; Scale: 1:5,000,000.; Size: 64.4 x 89.4 cm.; Colored.
      Presented by Alban W. Hoopes, February 1940.
    - ... Map of the present seat of war, between the Russians, Poles, and Turks... By Andrew Drury. N.p.: n.d. Second ed., 286; 2 sheets.; Size: 84.3 x 141 cm.; Colored.; Andrew Drury.; J. Caldwell and T. W. Tueur, Jr.
    - Le royaume de Boheme divisée en ses douze cercles. Carte réduite sur celle de 25 feuilles par Müller. Amsterdam: Cövens et Mortier: n.d., 287; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 4 Bohemian leagues.; Size: 47.1 x 54.8 cm.; Colored.; Müller.
  - Germany
    - [Map of Germany]. N.p.: [Senex and Maxwell: 1716]., [ca. 1716].; 288; Scale: 1 in. = 20 mi.; Size: 65.5 x 96.6 cm.; Colored.; John Maxwell.; John Senex.
      Double line denotes Dr. Brown's travels from Norwich through Germany.
    - A map of the German empire divided into its circles to which is added the Kingdom of Prussia, the whole laid down from the most accurate surveys and chiefly from the map of Marshal de Schmettau, lately published at Berlin by the Royal Academy of Sciences by L. de la Rochette. London: Carrington Bowles & Robert Wilkinson: [ca. 1755]., 289; Scale: 1 in. = 18 mi.; Size: 101.7 x 119.3 cm.; Colored.; Samuel von Schmettau.
    - Basis novae chartae Palatinae... By Christian Mayer. N.p.: January 1773., 290; 2 copies.; Scale: Pariser toises, oder klaffter zu 6 schube.; Size: 21.5 x 32 cm.; Christian Mayer.; E. Vevelst.
      The Society thanked Mayer "for his ingenious performances" and wished to have "the continuation of his valuable correspondence." In return, the members promised that they "will esteem themselves happy in communicating anything in their power to assist him in the Prosecution of his Philosophical Researches." [Minutes: Archives].
      Presented by Christian Mayer, 15 December 1773.
    - A new map of the German empire, and the neighbouring states with their principal post roads originally published by the Royal Academy of Berlin. Engraved with several additions and improvements. William Faden. London: William Faden: 1784 [9 November 1784]., 291; Scale: 69 ½ English mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 63 x 73.5 cm.; Colored.; William Faden.
    - Karte von Deutschland in XVI. Blatt nach des H.O.C. Büsching Erdbeschreibung u. den besten Hülfsmitteln entworffen von D.F. Sotzmann. Berlin: Carl Jäck: 1792., 1789.; 292; Scale: Maasstab von 15 geographische Meilen [= 9.8 cm.].; Size: 97 x 113 cm.; Colored.; Carl Jäck.; D. F. Sotzmann and J. W. Meil.
    - A new map of the king of Great Britain's dominions in Germany, or the electorate of Brunswick-Luneburg and its dependencies. By Thomas Jefferys. With various improvements and emendations. London: W. Faden: 1789 [1 June 1789]., 293; Scale: 69 ½ British mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 59 x 52.3 cm.; Colored.; Thomas Jefferys.
    - Carte générale de l'empire d'Allemagne, par Mr. Chauchard, Captaine d'Infanterie et Ingénieure Militaire. Paris: Dezauche: [1791]., 294; 9 leaves.; Scale: 15 German common leagues = 1 degree.; Size: 177 x 212.5 cm.; Colored.; Bellanger.; M. Chauchard.
      Accompanied by: Carte réduite de la carte générale d'Allemagne, pour servir à rassembler les neuf Feuilles dont cette carte est composée, par M. Chauchard [61.2 x 72.2 cm.]; Carte d'une partie des Pays-Bas, pour servir de supplément à la carte de l'empire d'Allemagne, par Mr. Chauchard (incomplete) [39.4 x 39.6 cm.]; and Tableau d'assemblage de sa carte d'Allemagne en neuf-feuilles grand aigle par M. Chauchard [24.4 x 35.4 cm.].
      Presented by Peter Stephen du Ponceau, 1 November 1839.
    - Germany. [1792]., 295; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 110 mi.; Size: 17.3 x 21.1 cm.; W. Barker.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 7, opposite p. 696.
      Wheat: 752
    - War. Attack of fortified places [Philippsburg: 1798]., 296; Scale: 2.6 cm. = 140 ft.; Size: 16 x 11.1 cm. (Plate: 23.9 x 18.3 cm.).; T. Clarke.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 18, opposite p. 808.
      Wheat: 811
    - War. Attack of fortified places. Plan of the attacks of Landau in 1713. [1798]., 297; Scale: 2.7 cm. = 200 fathoms.; Size: 9.8 x 17 cm.; Size of Plate: 23.7 x 18.5 cm.; T. Clarke.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 18, following p. 784.
      Wheat: 810
    - War. Plan of the circumvallation and attacks of Philippsburg in 1734. [1798]., 298; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 550 fathoms.; Size: 9.9 x 17.3 cm.; Plate: 24.2 x 18.8 cm.; A. Lauson [Lawson].
      Insets: Plan of part of the circumvallation of Philippsburg in 1734; also Profile of same.
      Wheat: 812
    - War. [Two maps of the environs of Soest, Westphalia. 1798]., 299; Size of plate: 22.3 x 16.4 cm.; Lawson.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 18, following p. 752.
      Wheat: 809
    - Kort over Tønder og Lugumcloster Amter, samt deele af Haderslebhuus Apenrade Flensborg og Bredsted Amter udi Hertug dømmet Schleswig, under Det Kongelige Viderskabernes Societets Direction... Reduceret og tegnet af T. Bugge og F. Wilster... [Copenhagen]: 1805., 300; Scale: 2 Danish mi. = 24,000 Danish ells.; Size: 56.5 x 85 cm.; G. N. Angelo.; T. Bugge and F. Wilster.
      Presented through P. Pedersen, 1 May 1818.
    - Des contrées transrhenanes on de l'Allemagne politique en 1808. [Paris: Didot l'Ainé: 1808]., 301; Scale: 50 lieues en deux dégrés.; Size: 32.6 x 40.7 cm.; Colored.
      Surrounded on three sides with data pertaining to the countries depicted and to some of Napoleon's victories.
    - Karte der Regenhöhen Deutschlands gezeichnet von Theodor Schade in Görlitz. Görlitz: [ca. I860]., [ca. 1862].; 302; Size: 56.5 x 50 cm.; Colored.; Oscar Diessler.; Theodor Schade.
      For article containing the information on which this map is based, see: Goerlitz, in Naturforschende Gesellschaft..., Moellendorff, G. von, ed., "Die Regenverhältnisse Deutschlands ..." Goerlitz: 1862.
    - Geologische Übersichskarte der Rheinprovinz und der Provinz Westfalen im Auftrage des Königl. Ministers für Handel, Gewerbe und öffentliche Arbeiten Herrn Graf von Itzenplitz bearbeitet von Dr. H. von Dechen. Berlin: Simon Schropp'sche Hof-Landkartenhandlung: 1866., 303; Scale: 1:500,000.; Size: 78.4 x 55.6 cm.; Colored.; Berliner Lith. Institut.; H. von Dechen.
    - Geognostische Karte der Umgegend von Hainichen im Königreich Sachsen von Carl Naumann. Leipzig: Engelmann: 1871., 304; Scale: 3 cm. = 1/8 mi.; Size: 37.3 x 58.9 cm.; Colored.; Carl Naumann.; J. G. Bach.
      See: C. F. Naumann, "Erläuterungen zu der geognostischen Karte... ." Leipzig: Engelmann: 1871.
    - Geologische Karte von Deutschland. F. A. Brockhaus Geogr.-artist. Anstalt Leipzig: n.d., 305; Size: 20.2 x 28.2 cm.; Colored.; F. A. Brockhaus.
    - Germany divided into circles; with the kingdom of Prussia, from the best authorities. N.p.: n.d., 306; Size: 30 x 36.6 cm.
  - Poland
    - A new map of the kingdom of Poland with its dismembered provinces. London: Robert Sayer: 1787 [1 January 1787]., 307; Scale: 69 ½ British mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 47.4 x 64.5 cm.; Colored.
    - Poland with the possessions of Russia, Prussia & Austria from the best authorities. Woodman & Mutlow: [ca. 1790]., 308; Scale: 20 Polish mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 32.2 x 36.3 cm.; Mutlow.
    - Poland, Lithuania and Prussia. [1796]., 309; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 130 British statute mi.; Size: 20.3 x 16.9 cm.; Vallance.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 15, opposite p. 272.
      Wheat: 785
    - Carte hydrographique de Pologne présentée au feu roi Stanislas Auguste par Mr. le Colonel de Perthes, géographe de sa majesté... Cette carte a été réduite d'après la grande carte topographique inédite de Pologne, assujettie aux observations du Père Rostan astronome distingué, et rédigée par Mr. de Perthes, sur les plans detaillés des cantons levés dans le cours de 21 ans sous les ordres et par les soins du feu roi. Paris: Komarzewsky: 1809., 310; Scale: 25 lieues communes de France = 1 degré.; Size: 64.2 x 80 cm.; de Perthes.; E. Collin.
      Presented by Kamarzewski, 2 February 1810.
    - Carte des travaux astronomiques, géodésiques et topographiques, exécutés depuis la fondation du Corps Topographique, jusqu'à 1890, dressé par le Général-Major Koversky. [Ca. 1900]., 311; Scale: 1:8,400,000.; Size: 48.9 x 42.7 cm.; Colored.; E. Koversky.
  - USSR (Russia)
    - [The Russian Empire]. The European part... from the maps published by the Imperial Academy of St. Petersburg on the new provinces on the Black Sea: and, the Asiatic part... from maps published by the Imperial Academy of St. Petersburg with the new discoveries of Captn. Cook &c. London: Robert Sayer: 1788 [1 May 1788]., 312; Scale: 60½ British mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 47.1 x 127.5 cm.; Colored.
    - Ducatuum Estoniae et Livoniae tabula cum cursu fluvii Dwinae. No. 3. [St. Petersburg: ca. 1795]., 313; Scale: 7.1 cm. = 10 Russian mi.; Size: 49.8 x 57.6 cm.
    - Territorium Mesenense et Pustoserense cum adiacentibus insulis et territoriis. No. 6. [ca. 1795]., 314; Size: 48.8 x 54.3 m.
    - Russia or Moscovy. [ 1796]., 315; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 500 Russian versts.; Size: 16.8 x 21 cm.; Scot & Allardice.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 16, opposite p. 554.
      Wheat: 786
    - Geographical and statistical map of Russia. Map of the Russian empire. Intended for the elucidation of Lavoisne's historical atlass. Improved to 1821. Philadelphia: Palmer: 1821., 316; Size: 26.5 x 39.2 cm.; Size of paper: 47 x 52.6 cm.; Colored.
      Third Philadelphia edition, 1821—printed on Gilpin's machine paper by T.H. Palmer for M. Carey & Son, from the London edition of 1817, with numerous corrections and additions.
      Surrounded on three sides by printed information on Russia.
      Presented by Mr. Ivanoff, consul general of Russia, 1 June 1821.
    - Karte vom Ural Gebirge gegründet auf die astronomischen Beobachtungen von Wischnewsky, Schubert, A.v. Humboldt, Ad. Erman, und auf handschriftliche Specialkarten. Als Beilage zu G. Rose's Mineralogisch-Geognostischem Bericht von Humboldt's Sibirischer Reise. [1842]., 317; Scale: 1:2,000,000.; Size: 55.2 x 74.6 cm.; Colored.
      Inset: Bjelaja Gora mit den Umgebungen.
    - [Maps of Russia, northern Asia, and islands in adjacent oceans]. Gidrograficheskii departament, Russia. St. Petersburg: 1842-1885., 318; 43 maps.; Sizes: Various.; Various.
    - Carte geólogique de la Russie d'Europe éditée par la Comité Géologique. Par A. Karpinsky, S. Nikitin, Th. Tschernyschev, N. Sokolov, A. Mikhalsky, J. Mouschketov, A. Sorokin, S. Simonowitch, A. Konchin, N. St. Barbot-de-Marny, V. Ramsay, J. Sederholm, E. Federov, A. Gourov, and P. Armaschevsky. St. Petersburg: 1893., 1892.; 319; 6 pieces.; Scale: 1:520,000.; Size: 56 x 66.7 cm. each sheet.; Colored.; A. Karpinsky, S. Nikitin, Th. Tschernyschev, N. Sokolov, A. Mikhalsky, J. Mouschketov, A. Sorokin, S. Simowitch, A. Konchin, N. St. Barbot-de-Marny, V. Ramsay, J. Sederholm, E. Federov, A. Gourov, and P. Armaschevsky.
      Accompanied by a pamphlet of text.
      Presented by S. Nikitin and A. Karpinsky, 1 September 1893.
    - Tiefenkarte des Goktscha Sees. St. Petersburg: n.d., 320; Scale: 1:102,000.; Size of paper: 58.4 x 70.2 cm.; Colored.; A. A.Iljin.
  - Finland
    - Distribution des dépôts quaternaires en Finlande. Par J. J. Sederholm. Helsinki: F. Tilgmann: 1897., 321; Scale: 1:2,000,000.; Size: 57.4 x 42 cm.; Colored.; F. Tilgmann.; J. J. Sederholm.
    - Geologische Übersichtskarte von Finland, und den angrenzenden Landteilen von J. J. Sederholm. Helsinki: F. Tilgmann: 1897., 322; Scale: 1:2,500,000.; Size: 52.5 x 37.5 cm.; Colored.; F. Tilgmann.; J. J. Sederholm.
  - Mediterranean Area
    - A correct map of the Mediterranean Sea with the countries adjacent. [1799]., 323; Size: 18.4 x 40.9 cm.
      In: John Payne, A new and complete system of universal geography, vol. 2, opposite p. 346.
      Wheat: 860
    - Map of the countries found in sacred classic and ecclesiastical writers in their ancient and modern names carefully compiled from the best authorities and drawn by C. Wiltberger Junr. Philadelphia: S. Tiller: 1829., 324; Scale: 1 in.= 60 mi.; Size: 59 x 138.5 cm.; Colored.; C. Wiltberger.; John & William W. Warr, Philadelphia.
      Inset: Palestine or the Holy Land.
      See: C. Wiltberger, Jr., "Vocabulary of all the places contained in the map.. ."
    - [Map of the Mediterranean world]. Western part of the Mediterranean Sea with the coasts of Spain, France, Italy, Barbary. Eastern part of the Mediterranean Sea with the coasts of Turkey, Anatolia, Syria, Egypt and Barbary. [London: W. Faden: n.d.]., 325; Scale: 69½ British statute mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 51.2 x 106 cm.; Size of plate: 53.4 x 126.5 cm.; Colored.
      On each side are some statistics, etc., of the countries depicted.
  - Spain And Portugal
    - Plan of the River Viguo, and Port de Rande. Situated in the north part of Spain, in the kingdom of Gallice... by Joseph Smith Speer. London: Speer: 1773 [14 June 1773]., 326; Scale: 5 marine mi. 60 to a degree.; Size: 33 x 47 cm.; Hall.; Speer.
      Presented by the Direccion de Hidrografia, Madrid, 19 October 1852.
    - The kingdoms of Spain and Portugal, divided into their great provinces. London: Robert Sayer: 1787 [2 March 1787]., 327; Scale: 69½ British mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 47 x 64 cm.; Colored.
    - Geo-hydrographic survey of the isle of Madeira with the Dezertas and Porto Santo Islands geometrically taken in the year 1788 by William Johnston. London: W. Faden: 1791 [1 January 1791]., 328; Scale: 69½ Enlgish statute mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 58.4 x 114.5 cm.; William Johnston and Andrew Skinner.
      Inset: View of the city of Funchal; plan of the road of Funchal; plan of the town of Funchal by Captain Skinner, 1775; and two views of the island of Madeira.
    - Ilha de Leão com asilhetas e fortes adjacentes ciudade e porto de Cadix com seus baixos &c. D. Vicente Tofino. [Lisbon?: ca. 1789]., 329; Scale: 69½ British statute mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 42.3 x 33.3 cm.; Queiroz.; Vincente Tofino.
    - Mapa de las carreras de postas de España... por D[o]n Bernardo Espinalt y Garcia, administrador principal de los correos, y postas de la ciudad y reyno de Valencia. N.p.: 1794., 330; Scale: 8.7 cm. = 35 common Spanish leagues.; Size: 39.7 x 56.7 cm.; Bernardo Espinalt y Garcia.; Pasqual Cucó.
      Upper left-hand corner torn off.
    - Spain and Portugal. [1797]., 331; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 120 British statute mi.; Size: 16 x 21.3 cm.; Vallance.
      In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 17, opposite p. 619.
      Wheat: 796
    - The bay, harbour, and environs of Cadiz: reduced from the survey of Tofino. London: Robert Laurie & James Whittle: 1810 [24 May 1810]., 332; Scale: 4.9 cm. = 3 nautical or geographic mi.; Size: 21.1 x 28.1 cm.; Colored.; Tofino.
    - Mappa geographica do reino de Portugal. [Paris: ca. 1827]. 4 sheets., 333; Scale: Legoas Portugzas de 18 ao graá.; Size: 47.3 x 24 cm.; Size of paper: ca. 59.5 x 73.7 cm.; Colored.; E. Collin.; J. P. Cardozo Casado Giraldes.
      Contains historical and geographical statistics of Portugal by Cardozo Casado Giraldes.
      Presented by Cardozo Casado Giraldes, 21 September 1827.
    - Spain and Portugal. Philadelphia: H. S. Tanner: [ca. 1833]., 334; Scale: 69½ British statute mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 22.8 x 28 cm.; Colored.
      Presented by H. S. Tanner.